A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Special Collections, Signature Letters FA1480
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Special Collections, Signature Letters
1937-1998
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1480
6.7 Cubic Feet 15 boxes (12 legal document containers, 2 letter document containers, 1 15x11 oversize box)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at the RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by the RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necesary.
This material was transferred to the RAC in 2018 by the Ford Foundation and was ingested by the RAC as Accession 2018:060.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains letters written by significant individuals to Ford Foundation staff between 1943-1998.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas.
During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into four series.
The collection arrangement is as follows:
Series 1. Letters from Famous People A-Z, 1937-1987
Series 2. Signature Letters from Individuals, 1949-1998
Series 3. Mills Committee, 1969
Series 4. Oversize Materials, 1982-1986
Other Finding Aids
Finding aids concerning Ford Foundation correspondence with famous individuals and public figures include:
FA1411 Ford Foundation records, Correspondence with United States Senators and Representatives
FA718 Ford Foundation records, American Literary Manuscripts (ALM) collection
- Letters from Famous People A-Z, 1937-1987; 1
  Arrangement
  The original order of the letters was retained at the time of processing. Individual files are arranged neither alphabetically nor chronologically, but the additional description note can help locate the first instance of an individual's letters within a file.
  - Petition from Members of Congress - Congressional Fellowship Program, 1972 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Signed by: Carl Albert, Gerald Ford, Emanuel Celler, Martha Griffiths, Benjamin Rosenthal, Frank Evans, Shirley Chishom, W.S. "Bill" Stuckey, Jr., Lee Hamilton, Les Aspin, Ogden Reid, John Brademas, Paul Sarbanes, James Scheuer, Ronald Dellums, Melvin Price, Charles E. Bennett, Thaddeus J. Dulski, Don Fuqua, Manuel Lujan, Clarence Miller, John Culver, Thomas Foley, John Rhodes, John Anderson, Robert Mathias, Sam Gibbons, Bob Eckhardt, Neal Smith, Parren Mitchell, Silvio Conte, Edward Koch, James O'Hara, William Ford, Edward Biester, Jr., Torbert H. Macdonald, David Obey, Lucien Nedzi, Al Ullman, Daniel Flood, John Conyers, Patsy Mink, Peter Frelinghuysen, Guy Vander Jagt, Fred Rooney, Robert Drinan, Michael Harrington, Louis Stokes, James Stanton, George Collins, Thomas O'Neill, Jr., William Steiger, Sidney Yates, Jerome Waldie, Brock Adams, Thomas Rees, Albert Quie, Barber Conable, B.F. Sisk
  - A, 1959-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Adams, Joey – 1967,
    Aiken, George D. – 1974,
    Albers, Josef – 1961 (2 letters),
    Albert, Carl – 1970,
    Anderson, Clinton P. – 1970,
    Addison, Adele – 1959-1960 (2 letters),
    Aspin, Les - 1977
  - B, 1958-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Blixen, Karen – 1958 (4 letters),
    Bellamy, Carol – undated,
    Bundy, William P. – 1967,
    Howard H. Baker, Jr. – 1974,
    Bill Brock – 1972,
    Bush, George – 1971,
    Burger, Warren E. – 1969,
    Brademas, John – 1968 (2 letters)
    Bolling, Richard – 1974,
    Boggs, Lindy (Mrs. Hale) – 1974,
    Brooks, A. Gordon – 1974,
    Bundy, McGeorge – 1974,
    Beall, J. Glenn, Jr. – 1974,
    Breckinridge, John B. – 1974,
    Bowen, Otis R. - 1974,
    Bradley, Tom – 1974,
    Badillo, Herman – 1974,
    Byrne, Brendan T. – 1974,
    Brown, Dyke – 1974,
    Bumpers, Dale – 1974,
    Brzezinski, Zbignew – 1967-1968 (3 letters),
    Bunche, Ralph J. – 1966,
    Bond, Julian – 1970,
    Bischoff, Elmer – 1959,
    Bloom, Hyman – 1959,
    Black, Eugene R. – 1968 (3 letters),
    Bogdan, Corneliu – 1968,
    Bronfman, Edgar – 1969,
    Bernstein, Leonard – 1970,
    Biddle Duke, Angier – 1969,
    Ball, George W. – 1967 (2 letters),
    Breathitt, Edward T. – 1967,
    Beall, Glenn – 1971,
    Burdick, Quentin – 1972,
    Bennett, Wallace – 1970,
    Bush, George – 1970 (2 letters)
    Burke, James A. – 1970,
    Bayh, Birch – 1970,
    Baird, Bil – 1970 (2 letters),
    Buckley, William F., Jr. - 1984
  - C, 1959-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Cisneros, Henry G. – 1984,
    Cooper, John Sherman – 1972,
    Chiles, Lawton – 1973 (2 folders),
    Carey, Hugh L. – 1982,
    Cranston, Alan – 1974,
    Crane, Philip M. – 1974,
    Casey, Bob – 1974,
    Conte, Silvio O. – 1974,
    Cordier, Andrew W., - 1968,
    Curtis, Kenneth – 1968 (3 letters),
    Clark, Joseph S. – 1968,
    Cousins, Norman – 1968,
    Carlisle Hart, Kitty – 1968,
    Cunningham, Evelyn – 1968,
    Curtin, Phyllis – 1960-1962 (5 letters),
    Cohen, Wilbur – 1968,
    Campanella, Roy – 1969,
    Clayburgh, Jill – 1978,
    Curtis, Carl T. – 1971 (2 letters),
    Crosby, Kathryn – 1970 (2 letters),
    Camacho, Carlos – 1970,
    Cook, Marlow W. – 1970,
    Capp, Al – 1970 (3 letters),
    Case, Clifford P. – 1974,
    Cowles, John – 1974,
    Childs, Marquis – 1974
  - D, 1959-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    de Mille, Agnes George – 1978,
    Dole, Bob – 1972,
    Dominick, Peter H. – 1972,
    Davis, John H. – 1974,
    Denholm, Frank E. – 1974,
    Dillon, Douglas – 1967-1968 (3 letters),
    Dingell, John D. – 1970,
    Dreyfuss, Henry – 1968-1969 (14 letters),
    Duchin, Peter – 1968 (2 letters),
    de la Garza, E (Kika) – 1970,
    Dodd, Thomas J. – 1970,
    Davis, Ossie – 1970,
    Douglas, William O. – 1969,
    Docking, Robert – 1974,
    Dominick, Peter H. – 1974,
    Draper, William H. – 1958,
    du Pont, Pierre S. – 1984
  - E, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Ehrlichman, John – 1972 – (2 letters),
    Eagleton, Thomas – 1974,
    Egan, William A. – 1974,
    Exon, J. James – 1974,
    Ewen, Frederic – 1969,
    Evans, C. E. – 1970,
    Elliott, Osborn - 1971
  - F, 1943-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Ford, Betty – 1975,
    Fenwick, Millicent – 1980,
    Ferraro, Geraldine – 1987,
    Frenzel, Bill – 1974,
    Ford, Henry II – 1974 (5 letters),
    Flood, Daniel J. – 1974,
    Fleisher, Leon – 1964 (2 letters),
    Fuchs, Joseph – 1960 (2 letters),
    Flanagan, Edward J. – 1943-1947 (19 letters),
    Ford, Gerald – 1974,
    Ford, Benson – 1950,
    Ford, William C. – 1969,
    Fulbright, J. W. – 1967,
    Fascell, Dante B. – 1969
  - G, 1968-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Goode, W. Wilson – 1984,
    Goldwater, Barry – 1972-1975 (3 letters),
    Grasso, Ella – 1977,
    Glenn, John – 1983,
    Goldberg, Arthur J. - undated,
    Gilligan, John J. – 1974,
    Gibson, Kenneth A. - 1974,
    Greenough, Gary A. - 1974,
    Gill, Brendan – 1963,
    Guston, Philip – 1959, 1970 (2 letters),
    Goldberg, Arthur J. – 1968 (2 letters),
    Johnson, Lyndon B. – 1968
    Gray, Hanna H. – 1982,
    Gonzalez, Henry B. – 1970 (4 letters),
    Graham, Bob - 1983
  - H, 1959-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Hoover, Herbert – 1959, 1963 (2 letters),
    Hearst, William Randolph Jr. – 1977,
    Hollings, Ernest F. – 1981,
    Hart, Philip A. – 1969-1972 (3 letters),
    Houseman, John – 1967 (3 letters),
    Henson, Jim – 1979,
    Harris, Jean S. – 1982,
    Humphrey, Hubert H. – 1972-1985 (10 letters),
    Hatcher, Richard Gordon – 1974,
    Henderson, Vivian W. – 1974,
    Haley, James A. – 1970, 1974, (2 letters)
    Hammerschmidt, John Paul – 1974,
    Helms, Jesse – 1974,
    Hall, David – 1974,
    Huddleston, Walter D. – 1974,
    Hathaway, William D. – 1974,
    Haskell, Floyd K. – 1974,
    Heckler, Margaret M. – 1974,
    Hollings, Ernest F. – 1974,
    Hall, William O. – 1968 (2 letters),
    Hague, Raoul – 1959,
    Haas, Karl - 1965,
    Hoving, Thomas P. F. – 1969 (2 letters),
    El Hadj Ahmadou Ahidjo – 1969,
    Dillon, Douglas – 1969,
    Hesburgh, Theodore M. – 1972-1974 (2 letters),
    Hatfield, Mark O. – 1971-1973 (2 letters),
    d'Harnoncourt, Rene – 1967 (2 letters),
    Hechinger, Fred M. – 1967,
    Hamilton, Lee H. – 1970,
    Hughes, Harold E. – 1970,
    Heard, Alexander – 1970,
    Hoover, J. Edgar – 1971,
    Hawkins, Augustus F. – 1986,
    Hoffman, Paul G. - 1958
  - I, 1972-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Inouye, Daniel K. - 1972
    Iacocca, Lee A. - 1986
  - J, 1959-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Javits, Jacob K. – 1967-1977 (27 letters),
    Johnson, Philip – 1968,
    Jordan, Vernon E. Jr. – 1970 (2 letters),
    Jordan, Irene (sp?) – 1962 (3 letters),
    Jackson, Maynard – 1974,
    Jackson, Henry M. - 1959
  - K, 1944-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Kennedy, Edward M. – 1970-1986 (6 letters),
    Koch, Edward I. – 1970-1984 (5 letters),
    Kennan, George – 1951-1954 (13 letters),
    Klots, Allen Jr. – 1967,
    Kissinger, Henry A. – 1963-1977 (7 letters),
    Kennedy, Robert F. – 1965-1967 (4 letters),
    Khatri, Padma Bahadur – undated,
    Keller, Helen – 1942-1949 (6 letters),
    Kirk, Grayson – 1950 (3 letters),
    Kanter, Hal – 1963,
    Kimball, Ward – 1963,
    Kirk, Claude – 1968,
    Kilgallen, Joseph W. – 1974,
    King, Coretta Scott – 1968, 1969 (2 letters),
    Kreps, Juanita M. – 1976
  - L, 1960-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Lifton, Robert Jay – 1977,
    Luce, Clare Boothe - 1983,
    Long, Gillis – 1974,
    Leakey, L.S.B. – 1966-1972 (7 letters),
    Lamm, Richard D. – 1968 (2 letters),
    Lipkin, Seymour – 1960,
    Lateiner, Jacob – 1960, 1964 (2 letters),
    Lindsay, John V. – 1967-1973 (3 letters),
    Lodge, Henry Cabot – 1966 (2 letters),
    Licht, Frank – 1971
    Lennon, Alton – 1970,
    Larsen, Roy E. – 1970,
    Lehman, William – 1986
  - M (2 folders), 1959-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
    Folder 1: McCloy, John J. – 1966-1969 (4 letters),
    Magnuson, Warren G. – 1977,
    Mondale, Walter F. – 1969-1982 (6 letters),
    Moss, Frank E. – 1972,
    McClellan, John L. – 1972,
    McGee, Gale – 1972,
    Metcalf, Lee – 1967-1974 (3 letters),
    Mathias, Charles McC. Jr. – 1971-1972 (2 letters),
    Martin, James G. – 1974,
    Murphy, Morgan F. – 1974,
    Moss, Frank E. – 1974,
    Mister, Melvin A. – 1974,
    Moorhead, William S. – 1964-1974 (2 letters),
    Mansfield, Mike – 1967,
    Mosselos, William – 1960-1963 (4 letters),
    McNamara, Robert S. – 1969-1971 (2 letters),
    Montoya, Joseph M. – 1970,
    Monnet, Jean – 1966,
    Morse, Bradford – 1966- 1967 (3 letters),
    Morton, Rogers C. B. - 1969,
    Moynihan, Daniel P. – 1969-1970 (3 letters),
    Mundt, Karl E. – 1966 (3 letters),
    Muskie, Edmund S. – 1966-1969 (6 letters),
    Menotti, Gian Carlo – 1968-1971 (3 letters),
    Mead, Margaret – 1969,
    Moody, J. E. – 1968,
    Maheu, Rene – 1968,
    McNair, Robert E. – 1967,
    McKissick, Floyd – 1967 (2 letters),
    McGovern, George – 1968,
    McCone, John – 1966-1967 (2 letters),
    McDaniels, Joseph - 1966
    Folder 2: Mead, Margaret – 1963-1975 (3 letters),
    May, Catherine – 1967 (2 letters),
    Mathias, Charles McC. Jr. – 1967 (2 letters),
    Mathias, Bob – 1967,
    Massey, Raymond – 1963,
    Marshall, Burke - 1967,
    Mansfield, Mike – 1964,
    Maheu, Rene – 1966,
    Mackell, Thomas J. – 1967,
    Moynihan, Daniel P. – 1969-1970 (2 letters),
    Mills, Wilbur D. – 1967-1970 (2 letters),
    Mizell, Wilmer D. – 1970,
    Mondale, Walter – 1969-1975 (5 letters),
    Murphy, George – 1970,
    Muskie, Edmund S. – 1969,
    Mehta, Ved – 1970,
    Middendorf, J. William II – 1970,
    Matsunaga, Spark – 1974,
    Mathias, Charles McC. Jr. – 1974,
    McGee, Gale - 1974,
    McCall, Tom – 1974,
    Meese, Edwin III – 1985,
    Monnet, Jean – 1966 (2 letters)
  - N, 1959-1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Nixon, Richard – 1969,
    Nelson, Gaylord – 1972, 1974 (2 letters)
    Nakian, Reuben – 1959,
    Nitze, Paul - 1986
  - O, 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    O'Neill, Thomas P. Jr. – 1974-1977,
    Ono, Yoko – 1968,
    O'Hara, James G. – 1967,
    Ottinger, Richard L. – 1968 (2 letters),
  - P, 1962-1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Peterson, Russell W. – 1977,
    Pastore, John O. – 1972-1974 (2 letters),
    Pell, Claiborne – 1972,
    Pickle, J. J. – 1974 (2 letters),
    Pauling, Linus – 1966,
    Proxmire, William – 1969-1971 (2 letters),
    Papp, Joseph – 1967,
    Percy, Charles H. – 1966-1970 (3 letters),
    Profumo, John – 1964 (2 letters),
    Perry, Frank – 1963,
    Preminger, Otto – 1967,
    Pell, Claiborne – 1962,
    Peterson, Russell W. – 1971,
    Pearson, Mike – 1967,
    Paley, William S. – 1968,
    Packwood, Bob – 1971,
    Perkins, Carl D. – 1971,
    Peale, Norman Vincent – 1967,
    Piaget, Jean – 1969-1975 (4 letters)
  - Q, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Quie, Albert H. - 1974, 1979
  - R, 1937-1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Randall, Tony – 1987,
    Rockefeller, John D. 3rd – 1941-1969 (5 letters),
    Rockefeller, Winthrop – 1967-1981 (3 letters),
    Lord Romsey – 1982,
    Robinson, J. Kenneth – 1974,
    Rodino, Peter W. – 1974,
    Reuss, Henry S. – 1966-1974 (5 letters),
    Reid, Ogden R. – 1974,
    Rhodes, John J. – 1974,
    Ray, Robert D. – 1974,
    Rockefeller, Nelson – 1937-1973 (13 letters),
    Rabin, Michael – 1960,
    Rose, Leonard – 1962 (2 letters),
    Roszak, Theodore – 1959,
    Rockefeller, David – 1967-1972 (8 letters),
    Randolph, A. Philip – 1967,
    Rhoads, James B. – 1968,
    Ribicoff, Abraham – 1967-1970 (2 letters),
    Richardson, Elliott L. – 1971,
    Rolvaag, Karl F. – 1966 (2 letters),
    Roncalio, Teno – 1966,
    Roosevelt, James – 1976,
    Rostow, Eugene V. – 1966,
    Rusk, Dean – 1966,
    Ryan, William F. – 1966-1970 (3 letters),
    Reade, Walter Jr. – 1968,
    Randolph, John – 1969,
    Reischauer, Edwin O. – 1969,
    Rudel, Julius – 1970,
    Rooney, Fred B. – 1968,
    Redford, Robert – 1985,
    Rockefeller, John D. "Jay" IV - 1970
  - S, 1963-1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Shultz, George P. – 1986,
    Smith, Jean Kennedy – 1977,
    Stevens, Ted – 1972,
    Stafford, Robert T. – 1972,
    Stevenson, Adlai – 1973,
    Stern, Isaac – 1982,
    Sexton, Anne – 1969,
    Schaefer, William – 1974,
    Satterfield, David III – 1974,
    Steiger, William A. – 1974,
    Shapp, Milton J. – 1974,
    Seibels, George G. Jr. – 1974,
    Sparkman, John – 1974,
    Stokes, Louis – 1974,
    Smith, Margaret Chase – 1970,
    Shanker, Albert – 1968,
    Sawyer, Grant – 1965,
    Schary, Dore – 1968-1969 (3 letters),
    Scheuer, James – 1965-1969 (4 letters),
    Screvane, Paul – 1964,
    Seaborg, Glenn T. – 1967,
    Shriver, Sargent – 1965-1975 (6 letters),
    Skinner, B. F. – 1969
    Soedjatmoko - 1969,
    Sorensen, Theodore – 1966-1969 (2 letters)
    Staebler, Neil – 1964 (3 letters),
    Steinway, Henry Z. – 1967,
    Stokowski, Leopold – 1969,
    Sutton, Percy E. – 1969,
    Symington, James E. – 1966 (2 letters),
    Symington, Stuart – 1971,
    Stevens, Ted – 1970,
    Shumlin, Herman – 1969,
    Smith, Margaret Chase – 1965-1970 (3 letters),
    Sanford, Terry – 1971-1972 (9 letters),
    Scott, Robert W. – 1969
    Schlesinger, James R. – 1971
    Salk, Jonas – 1963,
    Steinem, Gloria – 1976, 1980 (2 letters),
    Shriver, Robert Sargent - 1977
  - T, 1966-1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Talcott, Burt L. – 1967,
    Talmadge, Herman E. – 1974 (2 letters),
    Taylor, Billy – 1981, 1986 (2 letters),
    Thone, Charles – 1974,
    Thurmond, Strom – 1970-1981 (3 letters),
    Truman, Harry – 1962,
    Taft, Robert – 1972, 1974 (2 letters),
    Testerman, Kyle C. – 1974,
    Tydings, Joseph D. – 1971,
    Taylor, Max – 1966,
    Tharp, Twyla – 1969,
    Tobin, James – 1961-1966 (3 letters),
    Todd, Paul H. – 1966 (2 letters),
    Tolstoy, Alexandra – 1966 (2 letters),
    Tugwell, Rexford G. – 1967,
    Tydings, Joseph D. – 1968 (2 letters),
    Thomas, Lowell - 1968
  - U, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Udall, Morris K. - 1972-1976 (3 letters)
  - V, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Van Devere, Trish – 1969,
    Von Karajan Stiftung, Herbert – 1969,
    Van Deerlin, Lionel – 1967
  - W, 1966-1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Williams, Harrison A. Jr. – 1972,
    West, John C. – 1974,
    Winn, Larry Jr. – 1974,
    Williams, Lee – 1974,
    Wallace, George C. – 1974,
    Walker, Dan – 1974,
    White, Kevin H. – 1974,
    Washington, Walter E. – 1974,
    Whitehead, Clay T. – 1970,
    Wriston, Walter B. – 1971,
    Weicker, Lowell P. – 1967,
    Weltner, Charles Longstreet – 1966,
    Wilkins, Roy – 1975 (2 letters),
    Williams, Harrison Jr. – 1967,
    Wilson, Bob – 1967,
    Woodcock, Leonard – 1965,
    Wyzanski, Charles E. – 1967,
    Watson, Arthur K. – 1968,
    Waldheim, Kurt – 1972,
    White, Theodore – 1976,
    Weinberger, Caspar - 1984
  - Y, 1961-1974 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Young, Whitney M. Jr.– 1967-1969 (5 letters),
    Yunich, David L. – 1968,
    Yunkers, Adja – 1959,
    Yarmolinsky, Adam – 1961,
    Young, Andrew – 1974,
    Young, Milton R. – 1972,
- Signature Letters from Individuals, 1949-1998; 2
  Most of the letters within this series were organized by the Ford Foundation into individual folders that describe the letter's author, addressee, date, extent, and point of origin on the front cover.
  The last group of files in the series contains correspondence that was grouped with this series' signature letters but for the most part, was not organized in the same way as the other letters. Ford may have been in the process of preparing these letters to fit into its established system of arrangement.
  - B - Individuals, 1962-1970 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Battle, Lucius Durham - 1964
    Beck, Julian - 1962
    Bing, Rudolf - 1968
    Black, Eugene Robert - 1963
    Blanton, Ray - 1967
    Blaustein, Jacob - 1966
    Bloom, Julius - 1964
    Brademas, John - 1966-1969 (2 letters)
    Brooke, Edward William - 1967-1969 (2 letters)
    Brown, George Edward, Jr. - 1967
    Brown, Harold - 1970 (2 letters)
    Bruce, David - 1965-1966 (3 letters)
    Brzezinski, Zbigniew - 1965
    Buchanan, James McGill - 1965
    Burden, Carter - 1969
    Butz, Earl Lauer - 1963-1966 (4 letters)
  - C - Individuals, 1963-1973 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Califano, Joseph Anthony, Jr. - 1968-1969 (2 letters)
    Casey, Robert Randolph - 1966
    Caitlin, George Edward Gordon - 1966 (2 letters)
    Coles, Robert Martin - 1973
    Connor, John Thomas - 1966
    Copland, Aaron - 1967
    Crowther, Bosley - 1963
  - D - Individuals, 1963-1970 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Disney, Walt - 1963
    Duke, Angier Biddle - 1966-1970 (2 letters)
    Dungan, Ralph Anthony - 1966
    Dunlop, John Thomas - 1966
    DuPont, Pierre Samuel - 1963
  - Ea-Ei - Individuals (2 folders), 1952-1967 (Box 3, Folder 33-34)
    Eames, Charles - 1962
    Eaton, Cyrus Stephen - 1957 (2 letters)
    Eban, Abba - 1952-1961 (9 letters)
    Edel, Leon Joseph - 1958
    Edmondson, Edmond - 1959 (2 letters)
    Edmondson, James Howard - 1959
    Einstein, Albert - 1952
    Eisenhower, Dwight David - 1952-1958 (4 letters)
    Eisenhower, Milton Stover - 1952-1967 (26 letters)
  - El-Ev - Individuals, 1958-1966 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Elliott, Carl - 1959 (2 letters)
    Ellman, Richard - 1958
    Engel, Lehman - 1961
    Engle, Paul - 1963
    Erdman, David V. - 1960
    Ethridge, Mark Foster - 1962 (2 letters)
    Evans, Daniel Jackson - 1965-1966 (2 letters)
    Evergood, Philip - 1959 (2 letters)
  - Fa-Fo - Individuals (2 folders), 1949-1967 (Box 3, Folder 36-37)
    Fadiman, Clifton - 1965
    Fairbank, John King - 1959-1961 (4 letters)
    Farrar, John Chipman - 1961 (3 letters)
    Feldman, Myer - 1963
    Ferrer, Jose - 1959
    Fiedler, Arthur - 1959
    Finkelstein, Louis - 1966 (2 letters)
    Fleming, Arthur S. - 1960
    Folsom, Marion Bayard - 1959
    Fonda, Henry - 1967
    Fong, Hiram Lum - 1960
    Foote, Freeman - 1961 (2 letters)
    Ford, Benson - 1961
    Ford, Cristina (Mrs. Henry Ford II) - undated
    Ford, Eleanor Lowtian Clay - (Mrs. Edsel B.) 1956
    Ford, Gerald Rudolph, Jr. - 1959
    Ford, Henry II - 1949-1962 (10 letters)
    Ford, William David - 1966
    Fortas, Abe - 1960
  - Fr-Fu - Individuals (3 folders), 1951-1967 (Box 4, Folder 38-40)
    Frankenstein, Alfred V. - 1960-1962 (10 letters)
    Frankfurter, Felix - 1960-1962 (4 letters)
    Freeman, Orville Lothrop - 1957-1958 (3 letters)
    Freud, Anna - 1955-1963 (25 letters)
    Freundlich, August Ludwig - 1962
    Friedman, Milton - 1966
    Frondizi, Risieri - 1959-1960 (3 letters)
    Fulbright, James William - 1951-1967 (19 letters)
  - Ga-Gl - Individuals (2 folders), 1951-1998 (Box 4, Folder 41-42)
    Gabo, Naum - 1959
    Gaitskell, Hugh - 1959
    Galbraith, John Kenneth - 1951-1961 (7 letters)
    Gallup, George - 1955
    Glanville-Hicks, Peggy - 1961
    Gardner, John William - 1959-1965 (15 letters)
    Gatch, Lee - 1959
    Geisel, Theodor Seuss (Dr. Seuss) - 1955
    Ghiselin, Brewster - 1958
    Ginzburg, Ralph - 1959
    Giroux, Robert - 1959
    Giuliani, Rudolph W. - 1998
    Glaser, Milton - 1966
    Glazer, Nathan - 1963
  - Go-Gu - Individuals, 1951-1998 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    Goheen, Robert Francis - 1958-1964 (3 letters)
    Goldberg, Arthur Joseph - 1961-1967 (5 letters)
    Goldwater, Barry - 1963
    Goldwyn, Samuel - 1951-1955 (3 letters)
    Goodrich, Lloyd - 1960
    Gordon, Kermit - 1967
    Gore, Albert - 1966
    Gould, Samuel Brookner - 1967 (2 letters)
    Grace, J. Peter - 1961
    Graham, Katharine - 1966
    Graham, Martha - 1961-1965 (2 letters)
    Grant, Ulysses S., III - 1960
    Gruening, Ernest - 1965-1966 (3 letters)
    Gubser, Charles S. - 1957
    Guston, Philip - 1958
  - Haa-Han - Individuals, 1953-1966 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    Haas, Karl - 1964
    Hagen, Uta - 1958-1965 (4 letters)
    Hahn, Otto - 1955-1956 (5 letters)
    Hammarskjold, Dag - 1953-1961 (10 letters)
    Hansen, Clifford Peter - 1966
    Hanson, Howard - 1961
  - Har-Hec - Individuals, 1955-1968 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    Harewood, George Henry Hubert Lascelles, Seventh Earl of - 1966
    Harlech, (Lord) David - 1968
    Harriman, William Averell - 1957-1964 (6 letters)
    Harris, Fred R. – 1967 (2 letters)
    Harris, LaDonna (Mrs. Fred R. Harris) - 1967
    Harrison, Albertis Sydney Jr. - 1964
    Hart, Philip A. - 1962
    Hatfield, Mark O. - 1966-1967 (2 letters)
    Hayden, Carl - 1957
    Hayes, Samuel Perkins - 1967
    Hays, Wayne Levere - 1955 (3 letters)
    Heard, Alexander - 1961 (3 letters)
    Hearnes, Warren Eastman - 1965
    Heath, Edward - 1966
    Heckscher, August - 1962-1963 (2 letters)
  - Hei-Hi - Individuals, 1952-1965 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Heiskell, Andrew - 1962
    Henderson, Vivian Wilson - 1966